<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phones on Harecoded</title>
    <link>https://www.harecoded.com/tags/phones/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Phones on Harecoded</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 17:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.harecoded.com/tags/phones/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Iphone europeo libre y sin permanencia con Symio</title>
      <link>https://www.harecoded.com/iphone-europeo-libre-permanencia-symio-136763/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2008 17:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.harecoded.com/iphone-europeo-libre-permanencia-symio-136763/</guid>
      <description>Parece que los señores de Simyo (del que ya hemos dicho alguna cosa) están vendiendo en su portal los Iphone liberados al módico precio de 599€  Esto va a ser divertido: Veremos lo que hace Movistar al respeto y como empieza el carrusel de precios de iphone segunda mano. De momento parece que symio no le está dando demasiado bombo...  Yo seguiré con mi teléfono antediluviano, pero para el que tenga ganas de gastar:  https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic keylock for windows mobile smartphone edition</title>
      <link>https://www.harecoded.com/automatic-keylock-for-windows-mobile-smartphone-edition-96353/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.harecoded.com/automatic-keylock-for-windows-mobile-smartphone-edition-96353/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m having some fun testing a Samsung i600 (a.k.a. Blackjack) windows mobile smartphone edition. I will probably sell it to someone else who has more respect for Microsoft software, but the Samsung hardware is top notch nonetheless, and I&#39;m liking the device more and more.
Samsung tries very hard to disguise windows on this mobile, and the result is very good, frankly. Just like Nokia&#39;s Symbian 3rd edition mobiles, this Samsung i600 comes with no automatic keylock, which is INSANE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Como se formatea un Samsung SGH-i600v</title>
      <link>https://www.harecoded.com/se-formatea-samsung-sgh-i600v-96352/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.harecoded.com/se-formatea-samsung-sgh-i600v-96352/</guid>
      <description>Para formatear un tel&amp;eacute;fono (hard reset) samsung sgh i600v como los que proporciona Vodafone, hay que hacer un ejercicio de dedos muy interesante. Primero de todo apagar el tel&amp;eacute;fono, y a continuaci&amp;oacute;n pulsar simult&amp;aacute;neamente TODO esto:
  Arriba Ok (si tienes un dedo gordo pues ya est&amp;aacute;n estos dos) N&amp;uacute;mero 0 Bot&amp;oacute;n volver (el del lateral debajo de la rueda)&amp;nbsp; Sin soltar todo esto dejar pulsado el bot&amp;oacute;n de encendido (igual necesitas un pi&amp;eacute;)&amp;nbsp;   Te saldr&amp;aacute; un mensaje con una tipografia de dudosa seriedad indic&amp;aacute;ndote que presiones el n&amp;uacute;mero 1 si quieres seguir con la broma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to convert MP3 to AAC, or how to set MP3 as ringtone in your mobile phone</title>
      <link>https://www.harecoded.com/how-to-convert-mp3-to-aac-or-how-to-set-mp3-as-ringtone-in-your-mobile-phone-96342/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.harecoded.com/how-to-convert-mp3-to-aac-or-how-to-set-mp3-as-ringtone-in-your-mobile-phone-96342/</guid>
      <description>As if I were a teenager, yesterday I found an mp3 song that I hadn&#39;t heard in maybe ten years and a smile came to my face when I imagined that it could be played in my mobile when I need a loud tone (I am on of those who preffer having it silent all the time)
So I passed the MP3 directly to the mobile but it failed, the mobile can play it but can&#39;t be set as ringtone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A fantastic rss reader: readermini.com</title>
      <link>https://www.harecoded.com/fantastic-rss-reader-readerminicom-96339/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.harecoded.com/fantastic-rss-reader-readerminicom-96339/</guid>
      <description>I have been searching for a good rss reader since I switched my Nokia N800 for a Nokia 770, as the latter doesn&#39;t come with a default application for handling news feeds. And since I had already found a truly perfect image viewer, this became the last software I needed to complete what was a fantastic mobile computer by the way.
I am a big fan of Google Reader, to the point that I stopped using Netnewswire, one of the best Mac OSX apps in my opinion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Changed my brand new Nokia N800 For a 770 (and something more)</title>
      <link>https://www.harecoded.com/why-i-changed-my-brand-new-nokia-n800-for-770-and-something-more-96334/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.harecoded.com/why-i-changed-my-brand-new-nokia-n800-for-770-and-something-more-96334/</guid>
      <description>Nokia had a relative success selling the first incarnation of its Internet tablet concept: the Nokia 770.
Quietly and without much advertising, the company managed to grab the attention of a lot of geeks (mostly in the Linux domain) who quickly saw a device full of software hackabilities (a.k.a. possibilities). That is exactly the level of attention that Palm pretends/needs to make the Foleo the start of a successful line of products, but if they do not opensource its.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gmail en Nokia e61</title>
      <link>https://www.harecoded.com/gmail-nokia-e61-96324/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.harecoded.com/gmail-nokia-e61-96324/</guid>
      <description>Hace tiempo que no publicaba, pero os aseguro que esta vez ha sido por una buena causa... estoy configurando mi nuevo gadget, un Nokia e61, que finalmente y por lo que estoy viendo va a conseguir una cosa impensable... &amp;iexcl;desterrar de mi vida los dispositivos PalmOS!
Falta muy poco para que eso ocurra, un par de aplicaciones no m&amp;aacute;s, pero ya no hay vuelta atr&amp;aacute;s :-)&amp;nbsp;Prometo hacer un review m&amp;aacute;s adelante, cuando tenga una base estable de aplicaciones instaladas, ya que no quiero publicar la en&amp;eacute;sima versi&amp;oacute;n del art&amp;iacute;culo &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cómo conectarse a Internet con un móvil symbian vodafone y OS X</title>
      <link>https://www.harecoded.com/conectarse-internet-movil-symbian-vodafone-os-x-96323/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.harecoded.com/conectarse-internet-movil-symbian-vodafone-os-x-96323/</guid>
      <description>Si te quieres conectar a internet utilizando tu m&amp;oacute;vil Vodafone via blueetooth (tambi&amp;eacute;n es posible hacerlo v&amp;iacute;a infrarrojos, aunque es m&amp;aacute;s lento que el caballo del malo) aqu&amp;iacute; van algunas observaciones antes de que te empiezes a tirar de los pelos:
 Asegurate que tu m&amp;oacute;vil tiene acceso a Internet En el menu del m&amp;oacute;vil dirigete a: Herramientas &amp;raquo; Ajustes &amp;raquo; Conexi&amp;oacute;n &amp;raquo; Paquetes de datos &amp;raquo; Punto de acceso. Aqu&amp;iacute; debes tener airtelnet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>