<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ipod Touch on Harecoded</title>
    <link>http://www.harecoded.com/tags/ipod-touch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ipod Touch on Harecoded</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 22:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.harecoded.com/tags/ipod-touch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Shoutcast para iphone/ipod touch, espectacular app de radio por Internet</title>
      <link>http://www.harecoded.com/shoutcast-iphoneipod-touch-espectacular-app-radio-internet-183019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 22:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.harecoded.com/shoutcast-iphoneipod-touch-espectacular-app-radio-internet-183019/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;  Ya tengo mi primera app esencial para iphone/ipod touch de este año 2009: Shoutcast. Se trata de una de las mejores aplicaciones de radio por Internet (junto a last.fm), ofreciendo más de 25.000 emisoras de todo el mundo y con una interfaz de usuario fantástica para interactuar con ellas. Con tantas emisoras, no es nada difícil encontrar aquel tipo de música que busquemos para un momento dado: por ejemplo, buscad &#39;turk&#39; y Shoutcast os ofrecerá al momento un montón de emisoras de radio turcas, tanto las más comerciales como aquellas perlas en forma de música étnica del país.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ipod touch first impressions, a great experience so far</title>
      <link>http://www.harecoded.com/ipod-touch-first-impressions-great-experience-so-far-96356/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.harecoded.com/ipod-touch-first-impressions-great-experience-so-far-96356/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I said: ipod touch, I&#39;ll pass on this one. Can you guess what happened next? Well, it is pretty obvious... I bought one. I was extremely happy with an ipod nano 8Gb I bought 2 weeks ago, but a colleague of mine came to the office with a shinny new ipod touch, bought at the Apple store. One touch that had no TFT contrast problems, one touch jailbreaked with lots of apps, one touch with a terminal, ssh access and even an ebook reader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ipod touch, I&#39;ll pass on this one</title>
      <link>http://www.harecoded.com/ipod-touch-ill-pass-on-this-one-96351/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.harecoded.com/ipod-touch-ill-pass-on-this-one-96351/</guid>
      <description>Last week I sold my 30Gb ipod video for a bargain prize, just anticipating the shinny acquisition of a new generation ipod. I was never very happy with the ipod video anyways, being the main gripe its short battery life, which could only handle 2 hours of video playback and no more than 10 hours of music. I was never able to abstract from this issue, always observing the battery meter on the screen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>